Efren Castillo

www.efrencastillo.design

efrencast@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/efrencast 646-204-3974

I'm a UX Designer proficient in research, testing and coding. I have over 15 years of experience in visual communication, which has allowed me to develop my design and front-end skills. Husband, father, curious and bookworm.

SkillS

User Research

Personas

User stories

User flows

Information Architecture

Sitemaps

Wireframing

UX Writing

Visual Design

Branding

Product Photography

Prototyping

User Testing

Analytics

Website SEO

Bilingual (Spanish)

Tools

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe XD

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Animate

Adobe Premiere Pro

QuarkXpress

Sketch

Figma

inVision

OptimalSort

UsabiliTEST

Google Forms

Maze

UsabilityHub

HTML and CSS

Javascript and JQuery

GitHub

Projects

UX Designer

Stacks App | June – November 2019 🗹

UX/UI, content strategy and branding for a news aggregator app.

UX Designer

Cloudspring App | September - November 2018

UX/UI, content strategy and branding for a cloud-based storage app.

Experience

Senior Designer

JB Prince Company, Inc | 2006 - Present

- Research and advise UX/UI design changes to e-commerce website.
- Design catalogs for print and web reaching over 50,000 customers.
- Photograph and retouch products for e-commerce website and print use.
- Analyze data and optimize E-commerce to increase ranking position.
- Design ads for magazines reaching customers in various countries.
- Create web banners, campaigns for social media and email marketing.

Freelance UX Designer

Jersey Soundz Entertainment, Inc | 2010 - Present

• UX, UI, content strategy, and front-end for a DJ company.

Freelance UX Designer

JD Monzón Photography | 2016 – 2018

• UX, UI, front-end, and branding to help launch a photography business.

Designer

Providence Public Library | 2005 - 2006

- Designed displays for the library and Friends of the Library's activities.
- · Helped patrons and assisted with shelving and repairing books.

Education

Bloc.io

Designer Track: UX/UI and Front-End Development | 2018 - 2019 Comprehensive design program combining UX/UI (Research, design, testing) skills with front-end development (HTML, CSS, Javascript).

Gibbs College

Visual Communications: Graphic design and photography | 2004 - 2005